# **Prateek Singh**

# **Product Designer**

sprateek0204@gmail.com

www.prateeksingh.in

9711960199 | 8467884193

# **SKILLS**

Interaction Design, Strategic Design, Research Method & Processes, Prototyping, Information Architecture, User Journey Mapping, Accessibility, Usability testing

# **TOOLS**

Figma Adobe XD Photoshop HTML5

CSS3
JavaScript

Microsoft Office

Premiere Pro

### RECOGNITION

## **Wongdoody Insta Award**

Awarded for my contribution in a high demand client work.

#### **Full Stack Designer**

Completed a demanding training to earn the above certificate.

Infosys Certified Digital Accessibility Associate.

# **Hobbies**

Blogging Cycling Cricket 3D Printing Esports A designer by passion and education. I have been working as a Lead UX Designer at Wongdoody since after completing my Master's in 2020. I have a knack for Tech and my academics and work experiences have provided me with just the right tools to humanize it.

# **Work Experience**

# Wongdoody | Infosys

Jan 2021 - Present

Lead Experience Designer

Worked with multiple Fortune 500 clients, designing across a variety of domains. Meanwhile, continuously skilling up through the in-house trainings and initiatives.

US Based tech giant

Working with a team of designers to create, maintain and update a major sales portal and system of products around it. Lead multiple verticals from conception to realization.

South Korean Multinational Conglomerate

Lead two verticals within the project. Designed 10+ standalone widgets and the webinterface for a call tracker API. Received a 94% approval rate from client.

• Dashboard for Logistics Company
Designed and presented native flows for a white-label product.

# Freelance Product Designer

Jul 2018- Dec 2020

Worked across multiple design domains including UX, architecture, branding and Industrial Design. The clientele being mostly early stage startups e.g., ORIS & SOMA.

# **Internships**

### **Evinix Design Concepts Pvt Ltd, Ghaziabad**

Jun 2019 - Jul 2019

Product Design Intern

Designed and prototyped 3 articles which later made into mass-manufacturing. Documented the entire process and presented to the graduating class of M.Des Students.

# Spacematters, Delhi

Jan 2017 - Jul 2017

Research and Documentation Intern

Interviewed 30+ people and documented several processes of a native wood craft — likhai. Co-authored the only comprehensive document existing for the apparently lost wood craft.

### **Delhi Development Authority**

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

Transportation Design Intern

Researched vehicular density and conducted traffic analysis along a proposed route in Delhi. Later, worked with Transport Planners to design and develop the said corridors and presented the design to the Lieutenant Governor of Delhi.

# **Education**

## **Special Program for Strategic Insights**

Mar 2022 - present

Center of Complexity

Rhode Island School of Design

#### M.Des | Industrial and Product Design

2020

Department of Industrial Design,

School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi — First Class with Distinction

#### **Bachelor of Architecture (B.Arch)**

2018

School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi — First Class

# HSC, CBSE

Delhi Public School, Lucknow 89.3%